ALOK KUMAR

UX/Product Designer

+91-8709237633 designedbyalok@gmail.com www.designedbyalok.com

PROFILE

[0->1 Product Designer] I bring an engineering perspective and creative problem-solving approach to create products and experiences that people love to use. Persistence, curiosity and an obsessive attention to detail define me. With a background in Computer Science, experience as a developer and designer, I am competent in all aspects of the design process. I love creating effective, intuitive interfaces. I like prototyping - it helps me think through interaction models and new possibilities.

PROFILE

I have experience working with teams to brainstorm and whiteboard concepts. I can create wireframes at varying levels of fidelity, and enjoy prototyping ideas.

COMPETENCY

Design Research Wire-framing UI/UX Design Interaction Design Rapid Prototyping

GRAPHIC

Figma, Sketch, XD, InVision, Framer, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects, Final Cut Pro, Cinema4D

PROGRAMMING

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git, MySql C++, Java, Python, React, NodeJS

I have worked with many different prototyping tools and frameworks – to avoid a full laundry list above, I've kept it to just my favourites. If you use a different prototyping tool that works well in your established workflow, I would be happy to learn it.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Banyan Cloud, Bengaluru

August 2021 - Present

UX Designer

Founding Designer. Built a suite of enterprise-facing SAAS product in Cloud Security consisting of 7-8 services. My work includes product research, ideation, wire-framing, creating low and high-fidelity mockups, prototyping and testing out the product. Closely worked with the developers and helped them in the design-development part. I was also responsible for creating an extensive <u>design system</u> for the product.

Sentient Studio, (Remote)

October 2020 - July 2021

User Interface Designer

Worked on various client projects developing UI & UX for various apps and websites. My work included ideation, research, wire-framing, prototyping & creating low & high-fidelity mockups. Worked on the Design & Development of websites, using <u>Wordpress</u>, Webflow as well as HTML,CSS, React and Vanilla JS.

Doortask, Bengaluru

UI/UX Designer (Contract)

December 2019 - January 2020

Over the course of this contract, I helped on 2 projects, a new mobile app and overhaul of the existing website. I was responsible for design research, wire-framing, interaction, prototyping and creating hi-fi mockups. Also helped in the development of the website.

UI/UX Design Intern

September 2018 - November 2018

I worked on the UI/UX as well as the development of their website. As a team I worked to determine features and user flows. I contributed to team efforts with interaction design, UI and overall visual design as well as prototyping.

UI/UX Design Intern

June 2018 - July 2018

Helped them initiate design process. Designed and built their first website. Also helped in other brand design materials such as investors pitch deck, digital marketing materials and presentations.

MrStudyBuddy, Bengaluru

November 2017 - March 2018

Graphic Design Intern

During my first year in college, I got this internship offer in a start-up. I helped to create an interactive native language learning app for kids. I created the wireframes, hi-fi mockups and contributed to the visual design of the app. I gamified the design to improve the likability and UX of the app for kids.

EDUCATION

B.E. in Computer Science

2016 - 2020

Anna University, Chennai

Higher Secondary

2014 - 2016

The Pentecostal Assembly School, Bokaro Steel City, Jharkhand